Passionate web developer with professional experience and driving projects through full lifecycle from concept to implementation and execution. Mostly focus on front end development and write reusable and modular code in Angular | JavaScript. Currently working at Amazon through KForce Inc. as a Web developer.

## Qualification and Technical Stack

- Solid experience with open source tools & libraries: Angular JS, Angular 2+, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, Protractor, Jasmine, HTML, CSS, SaaS, Web Services/ RESTful and SOAP/, React Native
- Flexibility and genuine desire to learn
- Strong problem solver with excellent team/partnering skills

## **EXPERIENCE**

## KFORCE INC. - AMAZON

Dates of employment: Oct 2017 - Present Position: Web Developer

Successfully designed, implemented and deployed two different web applications in very short period of time.

Worked on internal-facing projects for Amazon HR Services (HRS) to manage and keep track of available services offered by HRS for global partners.

Used angular 4 for front end development and Node.js/Express for developing REST APIs and serving static files for front end.

Used some additional libraries like Plotly.js and pivottable.js to build charts, reports and cross-tab reports

## KFORCE INC. - THE WALT DISNEY COMPANY

Dates of employment: March 2016 – Sep 2017

Position: Web Developer

Design the all work which need to be implemented for new features or changes that Business Units want and attend any meeting with Business Unit to understand what they really want from us. Develop and implement variety software package for website which is defined and documented in design documentation and business requirements. Also write some unit and functional tests for new features and implementations. Troubleshoot, debug and implement any issues which identified in staging or in production environment. Cut the build every week to deploy new features and bug fixes into QA environment which QA engineers could test and verify. Mainly focused project is called Landing Pages which parents have an access to their child's account and they can make a change to profile or change permission of child's certain activities etc. Used my high level of experience of AngularJS framework which is very hot in market nowadays to making the project more user friendly, maintainable and highly availability. Set of development environments is WebStorm IDE for development, GitHub for source code version control system, Jenkins for continues integration, Jira for project management, MacBook Pro for workstation and some other tools.

#### VASTIKA INC. - FIDELITY INVESTMENS

Dates of employment: JUNE 2015 – MARCH 2016

Position: Software Engineer/AngularJS Developer

Designed, developed and implemented a professional and production quality SPA application in AngularJS for internal usage. Build and unit-test automation system with Jenkins, Karma, Jasmine, e2e testing with Protractor and GIT branching for an efficient multi-developer environment. Developed RESTful Web-service using Jersey Framework for integrating, consuming other external services of Fidelity. Developed front-end web-based enterprise application in AngularJS/HTML5 technology stack. Participated in design reviews, code peer reviews, unit testing and integration testing. Drove technical decision making for matrix program delivery team. Worked under minimal direction to integrate internally developed, vendor application within the current systems environment and applications. Worked with systems analysts in digesting business process for mapping integration into current environment. Used Agile to ensure on time project delivery with the highest possible quality

## CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY OF MONGOLIA

Dates of employment: APRIL 2011 – MAY 2014
Position: Software Engineer

Designed, developed and implemented a web-based application for processing flight information. Used J2EE, MySQL and RESTful web services. Also built a mobile application through the entire development cycle including design and architecture, implementation and lunch. Applications are still in use.

Developed a desktop alert system using Windows system tray that notifies users when the application receives data from originators. This features made the company's business process faster.

Developed a desktop 32-bit CRC checker application. That checks all products developed and distributed by the company. The product's quality metric improved by 20%.

Developed RESTful API and a mobile application for distributing NOTAM (A Notice to Airmen). Pilots use this application and they can easily see the important message for their flights. It saves significant time, expenses and paperwork required to distribute the message in traditional way.

## **EDUCATION**

#### MAHARISHI UNIVERSITY OF MANAGEMENT - FAIRFIELD, IOWA

JUN 2014 - DEC 2017

- M.S. in Computer Science (in process of distance education) GPA 3.27
- Coursework: Enterprise Architecture, Web Application Architecture, Web Application Programming, Algorithm, Project Management, Modern Programming Practice.

## MONGOLIAN UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY - ULAANBAATAR, MONGOLIA

SEP 2007 - JUL 2011

- B.S. in Computer Science GPA 3.44
- Coursework: Operation System, Algorithm & Data Structures, Software Design & Architecture, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management, Interactive & Intelligent Systems.

# **AWARDS**

- Won Grand Prize in "Development of Java Enterprise" competition by developing a suite of e-Help applications including a mobile app, desktop app and web application.
- Earned 3<sup>rd</sup> place in "Programming Olympics" named for Atal Bihari Vajpayee.